bitsum.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy Policy

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Comments

When you post a comment, it is shared through Disqus, a third-party service. Please read about their privacy policy [here](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy).

### General

We will NEVER intentionally share your email address or any other information with ANYONE, ever!

Your personal information will always be guarded to the best of our ability, and we get NO ACCESS at any point to your credit card or other billing information. That is collected by trusted payment providers such as [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/) and [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/) on our behalf.

Like almost all web sites, we monitor our web site traffic. For this, we use Google Analytics. You can **OPT OUT** if you want to, by simply installing [this Google-provided and maintained plug-in on your browser](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). It is compatible with IE, Firefox, Chrome, Safari, and Opera. Google Analytics privacy policy is [here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html). This service simply tracks web site statistics so we can know how utilized our server is and how well we are doing at recruiting new users. Your name or other personal information we have is never transmitted to it. Only information inherently sent in a browser request is known by it. It simply collects anonymous visitor data, the same found in any web server log (e.g. 1,000 people visited today, that kind of thing).

We use Twitter, FaceBook, and Google Plus ‘Tweet’, ‘Like’, and ‘Plus’ buttons, respectively. These simply direct to the pertinent Twitter, Facebook, or Google Plus site if clicked. They have their own privacy policy, as with all external links from this site (which are easy to detect given our consistency in page formation).

We guard what limited information we do store to the best of our abilities, certainly better than most companies our size, and probably better than most large companies. We have our [Forum](http://bitsum.com/forum) isolated on a separate web and database server.

NONE of your billing information is stored on our systems. We store only your name, email address, address, phone, company, and license information after making a purchase. These are the bare essentials. For recurring subscriptions (rare, but we have a few), the payment provider stores the payment info, e.g. [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/) or [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/).

We do not sell or disseminate your personal information to anyone. In some cases, regional Bitsum resellers (part of the Bitsum network) may have acquired your email and have their own privacy policies. However, if you ordered through bitsum.com, then that is not the case. We send a newsletter rarely, but only with clear and functional unsubscribe links, of course. You can unsubscribe on your Profile page.

The software activation (licensing) process simply sends the activation code, user name, and version information. The update process simply checks the latest available version against the current version and then acts accordingly with our great single-click updater.

Starting in 2017, limited application telemetry may be used in some applications. Any data collected is only about what features are in use, or data to allow us to improve them, and none of it be of a personal nature (not even accidentally!). Further, it will be entirely anonymized and no IPs or licenses recorded in the telemetry. You will be told exactly what is sent in this future scenario by the opt-in process, so let us not get ahead of ourselves. There is no risk of data intrusion or privacy violation here, as we are talking about metrics like — “Is ProBalance enabled?” .. “How many times did ProBalance act?”… etc.. This allows us to improve the algorithm. Again, not done yet, and will be opt-in when done.
